All right good morning.
Morning my name is
...on path coda and I'm a program manager on the bluetooth team so
welcome to the booty session for build twenty fifteen so
bad you guys came out I hope you all-new that there's a whole and session going on the same time
...this...really appreciate you all come out.
So, today session we really fun we're going to go through the new features and api is
...make bluetooth great on windows ten we'll take a closer look at the
api...and see how you can integrate them into your
existing apps finally our partners one of the early adopters
...api foot marks is going to come out and share with you there experience
developing on windows but first I'd like to share with you why I think right now is
the most exciting time to be a windows developer using bluetooth.
...before that and ask you to please submit evaluation this will help
us tailor the experience for next year also be sure to do that before you leave.
Thanks so there's three reasons why I think right now is a time
of great opportunity for all of us.
Reason number one sheer market since the early days of bluetooth
...simply
an audio pipe it's come a long way nearly ubiquitous in the car
...current estimate actually put bluetooth shipments
and twenty fifteen it over three billion peripherals a huge volumes.
Reason number two for isv
on the audience bluetooth is being used in new
and compelling ways all the time so new scenarios are being enabled we've seen
bluetooth low-energy almost everything fitness wearables and health.
And, as you...in the past new scenarios means new opportunity for developers
to realize that vision case in point we had the microsoft band that came out last december.
...brand-new app ecosystem because they previewed
...sdk earlier this year.
The brand you ecosystem that's ready for all of you to party on...opportunity as well.
And, reason number three.
...reason audience...shake their heads...and, this is really important for all
of us developers and that is that with windows ten and the rise of
...windows platform.
We...have the largest number of bluetooth capable
of windows devices that we've ever had in the...so,
you can deploy a single app or single driver all
these phones pc's and tablets just
...kern upgrades that's hundreds of millions of bluetooth capable devices stats
...well so these three reasons share volumes
...scenarios coming out all the time and hundreds of millions
of bluetooth capable windows devices cause me to say that this is a great
time...developing for bluetooth and the best time to start developing for windows.
One of my favorite stories of a group of developers that's been able to take
this sort of opportunity and really run with it and.
Deploys solution that impact people's lives is
...unlock project sponsored by the
guide dogs uk in partnership with microsoft they took
...a unique problem faced by the visually impaired
that they're not able to navigate a new part of the city of
...solution...please let me just share a very short video
...to so sure what they do.
Build...and caller local train station.
Builds...has automatically coupled with the local train station system and provides
...with all the information he
meets regarding platforms departure time and any other...
As the group wait for that...receives and...alert gives
...exact position of his train carriage...the group moves to the right spot
...train appears why some time.
Take two paces forward you'll carriage...
...cap instead of
As an awesome use of technology ...they're doing a great job
And, so.
There was an early conserve video and since then they've made
large-size forward in other technologies well even involving aof three-d
...conducting headset that gives their users three-d.
Sound perception it's incredible but the bluetooth use there is that they have begins
...strategically around along the city that...project the broadcast the
...location and, we'll talk a lot more about this technology as a session was forward.
To deliver this sort of opportunity to all of our developers.
Windows microsoft how to deliver on a vision was conceived in early two thousand
...that of a converge operatingfor a platform team like bluetooth that
meant in windows...windows phone it we delivered
a converge radio driver start with the basics.
And, some of you may know from last year windows...one windows phone...out one we
...a partially converged api surface the background functionality
...still not on windowspc.
And, finally I'm so proud to say that in windows ten we have a completely
converged api surface that works not just on windows,
windows phone but on all of our devices from a small form factors like io
...devices and raspberry pi...to larger form factors like the surface.
And, our engineering improvements in just
...there are revamped feedback system will allow us
to get actionable a...insight
from ourself posters faster and easier than ever before.
I was actually one of the program managers for
the members of the bluetooth team that had the pleasure of reading through
all of your feedback and I thought would be fun to actually put
...some my favorite quotes on the screen for-you some of these might even be yours.
Some more
feedback was immensely positive really validated the work that we put into windows tent.
Some...was not so positive so, there's
...road forward for bluetooth specifically and we're looking to
our other engineering improvements like windows a service to be able to
deliver on features faster and better code velocity.
Some of the feedback was immediately actionable a lot of you ask for a quicker way to
turn on bluetooth we made sure that bluetooth within the quick action setting even on desktop.
Finally we had feedback from all of the world this
one particulars from indonesia had no idea what
...but through the magic of being translate.
You realize that bluetooth connection problems affect...all universal problem.
Thank you all for being with us since windows throughout windows
ten we look forward to your continued support as we develop on future releases.
So, with all of our engineering
...windows a service revamp feedback system.
What's new in bluetooth for windows tent I'll tell you we've delivered on a
broad-range of feature areas and bluetooth of audio features like app
...and wideband speech support.
We have
course back updates windows ten be course back for dot one comply
...my personal favorite being able to use my bluetooth keyboard
...phone to type up along email bluetooth hid from mobile is
on windows ten can be more excited therefore features up here
but I hope catcher I not just because
...bold large big...strategically placed on the screen
because the new the enable compelling new scenarios
...talking of begins broadcast and being able to do this in the
background taking advantage of our new hardware offload capabilities
...double-click are celibate more about...
First question what is a bluetooth...begin well.
Begins use the advertising packet.
Now I'm not talking about the advertisements
like madman style that you watch on tv consumer ads I'm literally talking about
the advertising packet that's been in bluetooth since bluetooth low-energy
to unique payload that that's advertise the unique
problem the value proposition of...technology.
Is that you can take this unique payload and
give unique give experiences to the user experiences like presence
detection as we saw in the earlier video with
...unlocked the presence of a bicycle
...begin the presence of a train begin pulling into the st surfaces unique
experiences to the user location experiences for instance so,
that's really powerful?
In addition to just presence you want to know whether the user is close to be can
afar further away so windows ten you get the receive signal strength
or rssi value of every advertising packet...
All right and overview happy and finally windows can be the
begin as well with a new broadcast api and publisher api is.
Use developers have the our to actually
...what's being...by windows this is great as well.
So, to enable all this functionality we knew
...has to be great in the background as well.
And, we can't live in a world we can have experiences for the customer where they're
constantly disturbed by...that doesn't matter to them or that they experience our
...just because they walk into a room crowded with begins so for that we worked with
our ip partners more closely than we've ever had to in the past.
Working with them allowed us to.
Develop experience so that use developers can write to an
...all the way down to the controller so
the controller actually makes decisions on which packet to keep which advertising packets to
keep which ones are throw-away this level of cooperation
...urban donahue team and really like to thank all of our isv partners
...for participating this throughout the release of the work they've done is going to enable really
cool our efficient experiences for all of our users that's great.
So, for all of these features
...make three major name space updates windows tent.
As we're going to move into the more demo section we're going to learn how these
api function.
So,...that advertisement completely
noose name space houses are powerful
watcher and publisher capabilities so windows can listening and broadcast.
Bluetooth the background
...face of completely converged in windows ten
...houses the new trigger details classes so that in the background task you can actually read
off the trigger details and finally because the bluetooth.
Background for tenses just hook into
...existing background task capabilities all the new
triggersfor watcher and publisher rn application model...background.
...the fun stuff...out to actually implement this in your app before I step
...visual studio I just want to solidified to topics.
We talked about it just briefly now but the advertising watcher
the advertisement publisher the advertising water will usually sit on a phone
pc or tablet and listening to beacons.
Are only three steps the setting up...advertising watcher configuring with
filters so telling us which patterns to look for in order to
get what's interesting for the user trashing your event handlers so that...response to
...an advertisement event and simply starting the watcher once you
start the watcher windows is...for beacons on your behalf?
Then we have the advertising publisher a couple quick
notes before I actually go into how to
a configure this the advertising packet only thirty-one bites and
...a system-wide shared resource so,
as we use carefully we have a couple of remedies for this which I'll discuss
...the respond properly the status change events but.
We really envision these api for single purpose focused use cases
...imbedded devices point of sale which is shown here.
We realize this...but we're working on...solving this and the next couple
releases.
To actually set up...advertising publisher has only two steps.
Configure with the payload super easy step and actually start
publishing and once you get the call back from one of our events from the
status change event windows is advertising on your behalf all right.
this demo I hope to accomplish a couple things with your.
For things we learn how to set-up and advertising watcher...going to learn
...configure payload published a
published advertisements do all this in the background us that users will
...so that the begin advertises will survive through multiple
reboot six months from now finally...have a little fun with asher and we'll integrate with
...some research over the visual studio?
And, we're going to go through this.
Craziness okay perfect.
Before we even get started developing for publishing watcher just the fact
that you're using bluetooth necessitates a device capability
...be sure declare device capability bluetooth manifests.
Now...way I set this demo...
Is I downloaded what we had on get...a so-if you have trouble following along
we're going to cover a lot of ground in the next twenty minutes be sure to go download the app on
...it has really well commented I descrip...comments us
so it's easily easier to read but a lot more details explain
there?
And,...add the address scenario.
First go look at how to actually set up a
...watcher like I said before there's only three steps configuring the
filters attaching event handlers and starting the watcher so,
let's go through each of those little bit more detail so the constructor
for your page is where I usually like setting up the configuring the watcher
And, there are two main filter types in windows...
The first one is a out payload filter so you can actually
code what pattern to look for in this particular example
I'm just using the manufactures specific data to code...filter
but you can use any part of the advertising packet...of other signifying ones
...to fields underneath the manufacture specific data that are pretty interesting just for
beacons in general that's a company id and the actual data
...company ideas assigned by the sig
there's a big web page with a bunch of company ideas you have to go register with them but,
I'm choosing and unsigned company values just don't offend anyone
...I have the payload that I'm looking for a simple
pattern one-two-three-four skip that in mind as we go on to publisher demo?
The second type of filter they proximity
...filter so based on rs aside values.
I found that anything above minus fifty
db m is pretty close to the to each other means the to
divisive close to each other something lower the negative hundred is usually
far but your mileage may vary so
be sure to test with your specific implementations of begins and your
appwhile setting these filters so there's a little more experimental for you all right
so now we've configured the watcher a filter.
Let's go on and see how to.
Configure the event handlers...
Bluetooth advertising water has to a events.
In windows tent the received event and the stopped event
...every time you get an advertising packet that conformance to your filter that
you defined inup above and the stopped event is really
great for troubleshooting your user experience so in case the bluetooth
radio's not available the user inadvertently switch it off ...apple actually
...functioning and we'll stop watching so implementing this event
custom event handler will help you catch
...caches problems but I'm going-to go ahead and only implement the advertisement
received because that's the interesting one that you can use to modifier functionality within
...so when I receive and advertising packet.
So, pretty involved code snippet
let's look at the beginning but all I'm doing here.
Casting.
...I'm taking the bluetooth
...advertisement received event args so the event...and then reading
of properties from all of them and that gets you all the unique characteristics of your advertising
packet so what you see here is I'm getting the time...so
whenwindows receives the advertisement the advertisement type this is signifying
it's a combination of connect table non connect table or directed
...undirected advertisements so that signifyingadvertisement types your
our society values...is used for proximity scenarios
and you get the local name which is a...portion of the advertising packet as well.
The stuff that I'm really reading off of the manufacture specific data as well so all I'm
doing here is printing all these properties of the screen but of course within your
app you-can use this to enable more cool scenarios so now we know
...we've gone our...event handler setup there's only
one last step when the user.
Clicks the run button.
We just need to make sure to start our water so windows
we'll start listening once the run button is clicked.
On the page...go ahead deploy this.
All right so we...foreground...
So, my run button.
We do get advertising packets.
Is actually not expecting this one of you might be running the sample?
On your devices but, let's say we already have...advertising packet that conformance to
our pattern if you look here the company id.
And, the payload matches the filter that
we're looking for a and we we've gone a lot of advertise markets all right.
To implement the other side.
We need set up the publisher demo so let me go and show you had
a set up the payload.
The foreground publisher scenario.
Publisher there's only two steps.
Configuring the payload and actually starting
...publisher windows advertises on your behalf.
Okay, so, that constructor for the publisher.
...now this code.
Looks pretty similar to the earlier code in the watcher filter configuration
that's because we use a container advertisement class that's just
a general class that you use the
main difference for the publisher is that we only allow you to write to the
manufacture specific section as well as any
unsigned values so in the water you
...configure filters based on anything based on the local name based
on flags stuff on that order but for the publisher usually right to the
manufacture specific sections the company id and the data in particular.
...payload and notice them
taking care to have the same pattern?
A as what I'm watching for.
We can go ahead and when the user clicks...button?
Going to start the publisher.
All right.
Now there's a sort of step two-and-a-half to this whole process which is you want to
troubleshooting in case...you are not...properly resource
by a windows as I said before thirty-one
...is a system-wide shared resource so there are cases where other
apps in the system are using the advertising packet already so you to make sure that,
you know?
That you're app is not being service by windows.
We have a publisher status changed event
...and implementing the custom event handler for that will allow you to cashew
situations catch if there's not enough resources or your advertisements
were just waiting some things on that order can be done in this with this event.
Right.
So, now we have to scenarios the fun thing about this being a universal app.
I can actually change my architecture in deploy twice phone.
Now the emulator whoops.
Okay, so, the...you can truly building deploy bluetooth
apps the emulator but it doesn't come with a bluetooth radio so what do end up happening is all the
bluetooth functionality will look like it doesn't exist.
So, I'm actually using a real phonewe have who appproject by
...just projecting it to the to my a laptop.
So, we have the publisher sitting on the phone.
...on here is that there's already advertisements...okay I'm going to run this anyway.
So, the program publisher.
What I might actually have a background process running on my other?
...second here I doubt any of you are any of you running the app on your
screens.
Okay,
let me check once again...work who ...give up right.
All right what is clearly running this app.
you can see the publishers working for someone else but as soon as high run the publisher
my phone I'm also presume the publishing the same advertising packet
... what we can check is the...society value this we interesting going-to-take my phone?
A lot of these advertisements okay we have to
...lowest okay we're getting negative forties so the devices
are really close and thirty-eight.
Now...move really far away.
We get into the sixties sixty-one
...to the back the auditorium we might even stop receiving advertisements because of our filter.
But, yeah, that's a publisher on the phone.
So, now, you know, how to set up a...watcher foreground publisher?
But, often the one-b can functionality pass reboot
and for users six months from now so, we have to learn our do all this in
the background is very similar very similar programming style.
Except now we're involving the background task capabilities
...move into scenario number three...watcher.
So, the background
watcher initialization is very similar to the foreground case.
And, the main difference.
...to constancy restrictions but there to capabilities
...the background the first is that for the payload there has to
be one and only one payload filter...is because we want
...our efficient experience for the users as well as a
focus experience because you're going to launch a background task do something critical
...interesting and then
close it so it's going to have one and only one pattern the other major difference is that you're sampling interval.
The minimum sampling interval in the foreground is actually zero you get every single
advertising packet in the background again in the interest of our efficiency
our minimum sampling interval is one event a second so you're guaranteed
...event per...begin per second but if you're multiple
beacons you actually get more advertising packets ...that was cindy.
So, another difference you were using the watcher trigger instead of just
our btwenty advertising watcher.
Now we just have to do some basic background task type things.
We define a task entry point so it's a fully qualified class name
...name space and, name of a class with
capitalization and everything we sure do that's just one of the common gutters and,
then declaring are background task in the manifests...through an extension capability
we've done some work in windows tend to actually simplify the developer experience
so we've consolidated a lot of our all background task types to one single one bluetooth.
Once you declared you've we've configured the trigger.
Task entry point and declared in the manifest
we want to have the user pressed the wrong button and register
a background task.
Again,...fairly...code.
...a simple operation...going to check if a previous task is already been registered
and there's some code above that actually does this visual look at the sample
and get him and, then which builder background task from the previously
configured trigger a as well as the task entry point?
Try in register it when the user it's
...button...there's a number of reasons that background
tasks registration can fail.
But, the one special case.
Is if the hardware is actually not supporting our new hardware offloaded
feature we talked about before we actually worked with...free partners to enable this but,
a lot of
our devices currently may not be upgraded to support the feature
the good news is all the new windows ten phone's and, a lot of our major
...of devices a lot of our major devices including the surface pro three
...all be upgraded to have the feature but,
you have to take care of this exception case a user installs
you're out on a device that does not support...hardware offload?
...so, now that you taking care of this exception.
Your background task is presumably registered and,
because all of you might not have hardware that supports
...I'm actually running this on the same device that was going out to everyone the hp
...we have a special preview api that were that
...demo in here which enables
software filtering so even though you're not running it on a device that actually supports
...feature the hardware offload feature this will all work till windows
ten officially releases at that time the preview
software filtering feature will be removed and this exceptional start being...
app so be sure to do this in anything that your coding up between now and?
Now presumably the user hits...run button your background
...registered what happens every time you get the trigger.
Well, then we have to go to a separate project that houses
are background tasks I'm not going to much set up a background tasks but,
there's some great...on the first...henry...session...talks really well about background tasks
and, I've link to some of them in the end of the session notes but when you
get the trigger we're going to do a very similar operations the foreground which is.
Read through the advertising packets and
...display properties on the screen that's all I'm going
to do my background task right now there's one major difference between the
background the foreground and that is because your task may not fire
every second andsatisfy your minimum sampling interval well actually
...multiple advertisement packets
into one trigger details.
So, what I'm doing here is casting the trigger details as
ourtype so as the advertisement
water trigger details and then like I said the main difference in the operation is that now you have to
instead of just reading off the properties directly you have to go in?
And, loop through.
All the advertising packets that might be contained in your event
arcs and once again on doing is reading of the time...the advertisement type...so,
on so forth and, printing into the screen.
This is where you might want raise a toasts perform a location
...of operation things on that order but I'm going to put into the
screen a cool thing about now having this in the background.
So, let me go ahead I like using
my phone as the publisher and having mypc.
As a watcher the great thing about having a background tasks for the watcher is
...close the app...come back to it background...so, the...watcher.
It's not going to be running.
And, when I close...of course...running but the background watcher?
...the rankings gets registering the
...registered you'll see sometimes you'll see multiple event counts if there is
where multiple devices in this facility but, then when I close the app?
And, I come back to it.
I'll still see my background task register so you keep getting those events...that's
...tasks.
And, now we're going to lose
do a similar application for the background publisher.
The background publisher very
...the foreground I'm it's basically combining your...publisher with your background
a task capabilities I'm going to gloss over a few
of those operations now because you just saw it with the background watcher.
Right some...configure the publisher the advertising payload that
I'll be broadcasting looks exactly the same as a foreground and,
then again do my special background task type things define the task entry point.
Declared in the manifest and then when the user hits the run button?
We do a some similar operation to the...
And, build build-out your background task with the previously configured trigger
...task entry point.
Now this is similar so the triggers in the background...similar to the events in
the foreground so you can think of the watcher events received
and staff as what's going to trigger the background task similarly background
task for the publisher is triggered by status changed events so the
first-time you register your background task the first-time the user...run your background task will
be called once because it's going from undefined status to started or
...and then future publishers status changes will be reflected in
your background task that's usually what I use in my run method
of all I'm going to do here is print-out
...to the screen is great for troubleshooting to make sure your app is constantly publishing.
Once you get the.
Once you get the event that your publishers been registered
windows advertising on your behalf and will continue to do so even when the app is
not the foreground I strongly suspect I had a background...running on my phone this
...which is why we've seen advertises the entire time convening
...debug I'm going to...deploy this to my phone?
And, we should have the publisher background
tasks scenario running on my phone.
Here goes.
...are not being...right now students.
I think I may have started...soon.
...I...background publisher.
To be cool if I could show you...I publishing...foreground the advertisements
will start and stop when the app is on the foreground.
Right so we're going to the...started.
We're not getting advertising...I think are background...background task...overridden
ok so in the foreground when we advertise you see the advertising start on getting
to a...by the watcher but as soon as I close the app
...navigate back home.
The advertising...there no advertisements being seen anymore however free
go in launcher background publisher.
A background task is registered and as soon as the
...registered starting new events note the time stamp right.
So, we're getting new events and even when we go...we close the app the appointee
...in the back stack will have the background task continue to run.
And, you'll see advertisements once again the time
...incrementing all right so it's a symbols that
watcher publisher being able to do this in the background.
Let's have some...with this ...users sometimes is really useful to get more
context I don't just want to know.
The payload and it's pretty tough to give the your user all this context that the
...can have just by a simply just simply through the thirty-one
bytes.
Microsoft has...service that allows you to paying the...
And, get back more context for the user so let's move into as
your integration demo all I'm going to do here.
Is take the first scenario so the foreground watcher
and instead of displaying to the screen right and remember the same payloads
one-two-three-four I'm looking for the same pattern instead of the displaying
received a advertisements to the screen...match that payload ...up to
measure and return string and get more context for the user simple ling query
and integrating with asher mobile...do this of link to the tutorial for out
...mobile service capability to your app in my session notes as well?
And, for this.
A simple ling query just to match the payload
ascended up pleasure match against my table up...
So, when I run my foreground watcher you see the same company id
a and payload one-two-three-four on doing the as integration demos taking that payload?
And, it's going to ping up to
...actually show you solve real...my as your table.
My actual subscription.
A lot of stuff going so when I get this payload one return this text.
Starting.
It takes a little bit time.
And, see if it's still advertising ok I'm still getting advertisements.
The last for the demo so is the so is the kicker right.
...see going to make sure I still have a payload up and measure do.
...just for a second.
Okay, looks like I'm not able to show you being able to co
there it is yes flo you...the advertising payload
imagine of the as...and now you're more context about the device is in fact
a bicycle...right but let's say you deployed all these
...of the field a and instead of embedding them
...bicycle racks all over the world.
...snafu the manufacturing area rasheed configuring
they actually put it into a different device what do you do then.
You go in and have to flash each of those individual...from
where no you can reconfigure asher to get the payload
and return something different in this case I'm going to go to my super fancy agile management council?
And,...in lamp posts all over the world...that makes no sense.
...reconfigure that's.
And, then.
Looking at the same payload right company id and,
one-two-three-four we're going to match-up to measure now you're bicycle
...is magically transform into a lamp post
...thank you thank you great functionality.
Great example of a company that's taken this idea and really run with it and,
...able to deploy an enterprise ready
...can solution is our partners foot
marks and please join me in welcoming up ceo for...pass on the stage.
You've ever seen anyone so excited about...bicycle return
...sliding my jobs of considerably more easy than cure
...coding but we look at the work he did a good work he did you think about
...that gigantic and obvious mobility global trend...the consumer side and on
the business side it's clear there's just a ton of value to be created by all of
...developers buinesses foot...for barks we saw that a while ago
and got pretty excited by that so we're kind of really looking forward windows enrolling
out all the billion different devices and there's
tons of opportunity for everybody we also...tons of challenges
number-one challenge there is in the consumer side we need
consumers to engage in the ecosystem so if you go into your app
uturn bluetooth off you go dark effectively this ecosystem can start to
will down so we need is developers to make sure that we do create value
...share value using this core technology so they stay
engage the ecosystem...eight-foot...we have this one term we...the yellow
...challenge basically I'm standing in the real-world and I'm staring at a yellow
...as developers know that...stereo issue in real-time so
...to me about the yellow issue not a minute later and as I move twelve inches to the right
when I'm standing staring...you talking about that and
even better is know who I am use my online personas purchase data
...who I am so I walk into any physical location you-can proactively start to
find the things that are of value to me this organic proactive search in the
...bring that back to me help me find that product in
any physical location vast horseshoe...starts to get created.
And, we actually we...very hard for...to make that happen when
you do that good things will start to happen massive developer opportunity...role
...one-word sum it up is modernization the way to make money when you do
well this will happen we've deployed
it nfl stadiums retail centers and malls already and you can start to
see good things happen in the app stores and with your app the number one thing is increase
app downloads so people know they're...more value would be...from their apps so
six to seven times more downloads...apps than on the
...enabled and that's huge it's a massive number app engagement
so session durations start to get much longer...the best way to think about this is
in the traditional world of digital media online advertising in mobile
ads...tend to have click-through rate of less than one percent less than one percent
and not very impressive but would be only enabled ad so this is a standing from
the lsu maybe a given ad for yellow
...that number moves the twenty times and sixty times
...orders of magnitude much better engagement you start to see and
then you have more downloads more value being created that fly
will starts and you start to see really cool things happen better ratings and around this
virtuous circle you start so it's clear there's a massive opportunity especially given mind
the windows ten that massive scale will start to see...forward so
early...real quick the reason I'm here is just a quick demo but at foot
marks were lucky enough to get involved with microsoft about a year-ago so we're the only
...to consult with them as they started to...solution in addition to
having all of the classic or cool features of...we as a
startup needed a few additional things which is make it easy-to-use I
don't have as a ceo of its tiny startup I don't have a ton of resources trying to
make sure everyone is really working well and really quickly and that was
...really cool...they did it took us just a matter of hours
deport over our android code point to the windows ten
st case magic started to happen we start to get
...contextual returns we expect to see on the windows platform
saying that was extremely cool...this graph much appreciated so,
that was kind of a big easy thing to do for us and that brings me to the demo in
particular so we have three different things happening and, cured was talking about them I'll touch
on real fast because the demos kind of brief so in the background you'll see the
...broadcasting the advertising...you'll see the
sdk the phone seeing reading and watching talking to as
your that pingback the actual payload return so will move into the demo
here the...payload note here and hand-washing here and we actually put...beginning
...office and we enabled his bosses phone
where sdk...able to your...sdk...really
on so we saw over time here has a little bit of a hard time getting
to work in time especially relative to is boss...
construct bonuses are coming...hairy so we had no idea why don't we actually starts
give notifications secure and what is bosco smoothie office and then...real
...to be office and see the job so if you how the privacy invasion is
...to...value the value...the...so the idea is if he actually gets
in time that's perfect he's happy fully employed...even have bonus the
...if...then...evil
...in that case maybe or maybe unemployed tiny little probably after what you just said,
yeah, exactly so...run you log into the...what we've done is we have a beak
...out the middle the audience so this is pretty similar to the setup we have
...his office...effectively
...beak and represents your office okay we'll...you log in there will start
...on your perilous journey towards the...if you actually got
their time and see if you actually made in time so
...start the demo trying to sell me something time, yeah, we'll see if you actually get there in time
is your approaching we'll see...so notification
and let's...so sure unemployed use now
...lazy...here's a developer that's unemployed if you're,...
I thought I'd make it the whole time is yes you have we kinda had a little bit of...with coherent
but the reality is that with the platform they put together ease of use of the tools
...matter the...took us just a few hours...over...
You think about that...to get the keynote as one billion
devices that is the goal for one or two years out that's a massive number the upgrade
...windows ten so this is a great tool set
...massive scale for us to...for...so with that
...back here and I am also reminded come visit us at the insiders lounge
...the completion of this your thanks-a-lot...was great?
Moi sponges an you...
All right so I'll just saidregulates edit we
microsoft have worked hard to make it easy for you all to use
...technology we made it easy bye unlocking the opportunity of
hundreds of millions of bluetooth capable windows devices we made it easy
by a converging are api surface so you have to write one app
or one driver we made it easy to integrate with asher
a and delivery our efficient experience to hardware offload so go
forth...our api is give us feedback
...listening and if there's one message I hope you'll take away from this entire session
its that the...no longer the...
...creativity will...the potential
...thank you all so much for attending
...session before I take questions.
...want to say that tod myself and when the primary designers of
the...api...song when my colleagues will be out in
the windows insiders lounge so come by and cs afterwards?
A couple related sessions...click-through we have the app model so I think
the talk a lot about...I did not switch back to the
powerpoint you are looking a...the whole time beautiful
there's a couple related sessions with the background tasks and stuff andrew clinic income
large-scale great talk on monday
and, as we talked about with a huge opportunity with bluetooth development here's the microsoft health
...related session and, with...I open the...questions
...andrea...we have time for a few questions of please
go up to the front there's a mike right here I believe that's active.
Arthur's another one.
Tried...speaker michael's things being recorded sources easier.
That way...been...beacons for quite...and within the
kinda bothers me is you get your sort of not following what everybody else does
...be it seems like for example,
whenever you're looking for...to establishment that's right you could monitoring...range
okay now we saw one which I think is equivocal ranging from.
They're still monitoring or anything which is considered to be better...background
...useless ourthe other thing is mean we're talking about the advertise
packet.
...you know, there's a lot of stuff in there...the major of
...majored number minor number guid.
...gothic is composed things like that because I didn't see against augmenting of that either.
I see so in general with the windows
...can api is we follow the bluetooth...so it's a universal
begin standard right and, with that especially with the
...minor I didn't talk a lot about the other properties but if you go
and look there are a number of other properties that you can read off of that you'll get
to see so it's not I didn't demo all of those functionality
...I'm actually I'm interested in what you're doing this so combine
...outside...windows insiders large I'd love to hear what you're doing with begins and I'll try
and help you out and see if we can provide functionality right the next
...I guess in the back...out the first are you so for example,
on windows phone where your battery life gets.
Pretty significant hit from
...on all sides are you going to have a rate limitation on.
The background tasks or.
Once I I'm sort of hard hearing you from
maybe I think all I heard was that there's a our hit with the background task.
Is that so are you going to have limitation on how long about
...run or how many times you can get triggered?
So, I mean I'm not the best person
ask background tasks and in general because that's the general
capability I will say that there's work that had been done
in windows tento make sure background task has at least twenty five seconds
before the thirty seconds one of the talks...link to has more information about this but,
these tasks for begins a very short running right you want to get a
begin payload and then do something small like smart quick
...to the user ping up to as...things on that order so
when expected to exceed our system requirementsjust thinking that,
for example, when you're walking around the store...get a bunch of begins and, you know,
you're moving...can get pretty messy?
We recognize that there's there's things to do to optimize of act on
...lexicon...
...yes, that's...
Dimension that we have in the background...
...minimum...
Samoa.
...results.
Really...allstate more powered by increasing
...just...the first...about.
The format the types that you're talking about...types...
So, the...that herein showed samoa.
So, all those ...able...all the there isn't a specific.
Better thank you there is a specific...in terms of the buckets that the
exists for in...location but we do is we provide the our
society so you can do that yourself we are looking in the future at providing some sort
of bucking like that butts right now what we've heard in general like from our partners
...is that they actually want the raw our society so they can roll their own
and more improved rate ranging so you initially you can do...grown-up.
Are...enemy available for the windows desktop...organ have to be a
store yep universal...universal api so you can enable
on desktop perform...imbedded anything?
Sure, I have...
...to provide the ability to several records...load.
When using the front mike I don't know why
...back mike is just a lot harder to understand up here?
Wi-fi...a
...published...be able to several records and two-one payload.
...like to caveman effective dot...short name and several
Also putting multiple packets multiple data types into one payload
...the question do I
...shirt this is all documented on msdn right now if you go up to look at
...documentation before the advertisement
publisher currently or limiting the payload to manufacture specific types and also just
...proprietary type in the future will enable more as part of as we add more functionality for
it's like at server a lot of information kind of ...the existence of...bluetooth
...peripheral with which you can interact and that's not the case currently
with windows to have advertising api to services srs...and,
then as we...more functionality one...of...section?
Gaidar
...we'll be able...set of advertising and spending perimeters.
Like the interval.
No,...advertising...milliseconds before facets advertising
And, the next...we'll be able to use it watch a and the publisher in the same time.
Yeah, you were actually was actually doing that on the phone I had the publisher going
and back on water was...depends on the ability over the
...cheap to be able to...the same time.
Yes, and, that I think that capabilities in four-point-zero already and,
this over requirements.
For windows...requirement here and that's something that's
...tests so all the partners that we are the major
ip...partners that we work with...keep.
A and the last questions
...have lance the...networking...mesh networking.
That so mesh still something that's being discussed there's no official...for that yet but,
that's something that certainly we're looking at I think another general and
...question we're almost we're pretty much out of time
...into the red so if...more questions we find this out in the windows
...large...love to hear from you so, comes halo thanks guys.